Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Memoranda, 1915-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Memoranda 1915-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company.
9.34 linear feet Extent: 6700 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. JWT Memoranda cover the years 1915-1999 and include desk-to-desk communications collected by the New York Office Information Center and the New York International Department, along with other materials originating primarily in the New York and Chicago offices. The materials primarily include communications distributed from JWT management to staff, and cover a range of topics including new business acquisitions, account losses, company benefits, social and charitable events, staff and office changes, promotions and retirements, and commentary on articles appearing in the news media. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00729
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Unpublished materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for fifteen years from the date of creation.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Memoranda were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987, with additions in subsequent years.
Collection Overview
JWT Memoranda cover the years 1915-1999 and include desk-to-desk communications collected by the New York Office Information Center and the New York International Department, along with other materials originating primarily in the New York and Chicago offices. The materials primarily include communications distributed from JWT management to staff, and cover a range of topics including new business acquisitions, account losses, company benefits, social and charitable events, staff and office changes, promotions and retirements, and commentary on articles appearing in the news media.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: Domestic Memoranda, International Memoranda, Chicago Office, and New York Office. Arrangement is chronological by year.
Subject Headings
J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Management; Memorandums; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives:
Chicago Office Records
New York Office Records
Corporate Documentation
Newsletters
Publications
Staff Meeting Minutes
Writings and Speeches
Contents of Collection
- Domestic Memoranda, 1915-1995, (7 boxes)
  - 1915 Sept., 1924 Oct.-1945 May (Box 1)
  - 1946-1954 (Box 1)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - 1957 (Box 1)
  - 1958 (Box 1)
  - 1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961 (Box 1)
  - 1962 (Box 1)
  - 1963 (Box 2)
  - 1964 (Box 2)
  - 1965 (Box 2)
  - 1966 (Box 2)
  - 1967 (Box 2)
  - 1968 (Box 3)
  - 1969 (Box 3)
  - 1970 (Box 3)
  - 1971 (Box 3)
  - 1972 (Box 3)
  - 1973 (Box 3)
  - 1974 (Box 4)
  - 1975 (Box 4)
  - 1976 (Box 4)
  - 1977 (Box 4)
  - 1978 (Box 4)
  - 1979 (Box 5)
  - 1980 (Box 5)
  - 1981 (Box 5)
  - 1982 (Box 5)
  - 1983 (Box 5)
  - 1984 (Box 6)
  - 1985 (Box 6)
  - 1986 (Box 6)
  - 1986 (continued) (Box 7)
  - 1987 Jan.-Mar. (Box 7)
  - 1987 Nov.-1988 June (Box 7)
  - 1988 July-1989 June (Box 7)
  - 1989 July-1990 June (Box 7)
  - 1991 May-July (Box 7)
  - 1991 Aug.-1992 Feb. (Box 7)
  - 1995 (Box 7)
- International Memoranda, 1958-1975, (1 box) (Box 7)
  - 1958-1970 (Box 8)
  - 1971-1973 (Box 8)
  - 1973-1975 (Box 8)
- Chicago Office, 1980-1999, (6 boxes) (Box 8)
  - 1980-1982 (Box CH1)
  - 1983 (Box CH1)
  - 1984 (Box CH1)
  - 1985 (Box CH1)
  - 1986 (Box CH1)
  - 1987 (Box CH1)
  - 1987 (continued) (Box CH2)
  - 1988 (Box CH2)
  - 1991 (Box CH2)
  - 1991 (continued) (Box CH3)
  - 1992 (Box CH3)
  - 1993 (Box CH3)
  - 1993 (continued) (Box CH4)
  - 1994 (Box CH4)
  - 1995 (Box CH4)
  - 1996 (Box CH6)
  - 1997 (Box CH7 [RESTRICTED])
    RESTRICTED
  - 1998 (Box CH7 [RESTRICTED])
  - 1999 (Box CH7 [RESTRICTED])
- New York Office, 1978-1996, (7 boxes) (Box CH7 [RESTRICTED])
  - 1978 (Box NY1)
  - 1979 (Box NY1)
  - 1980 (Box NY1)
  - 1981 (Box NY1)
  - 1982 (Box NY2)
  - 1983 (Box NY2)
  - 1984 (Box NY2)
  - 1985 (Box NY3)
  - 1986 (Box NY3)
  - 1987 (Box NY3)
  - 1988 (Box NY4)
  - 1989 (Box NY4)
  - 1990 (Box NY4)
  - 1991 (Box NY5)
  - 1992 (Box NY5)
  - 1993 (Box NY5)
  - 1994 (Box NY6)
  - 1995 (Box NY6)
  - 1996 (Box NY6)
  - Worldwide office address lists, 1989-1993 (Box NY7)